JHON DEIBER DIAZ PARRA | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Montréal QC, Canada | (514)3461672 | jhondeiberd@gmail.com Portfolio | Linkedin | Github

PROFILE

I am a professional with extensive skills and experience in the industry, I have experience as an administrator in Microsoft Dynamics ERP, systems such as POS, eCommerce, WMS, and PLM for 12 years, I have experience in SQL database server for 3 years. I know Object Oriented Programming (OOP), different programming languages and tools that allow me to be a person capable of contributing to the needs of the company and its customers. Throughout my career, I have participated in large-scale complex projects, functionalities, and interfaces reengineering. I believe that innovation and continuous improvement is a success factor for organizations, which is why I tirelessly insist on applying these criteria in all the initiatives in which I have participated. I like to make a difference with my commitment, my responsibility, and my effort, and always give my best.

SKILLS

Web: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Web services API, REST, MVC

Programming languages: Java, Python, GO, C#, C++, PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, T-SQL

Mobile technologies: Kotlin, Flutter Control version: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

Project management: Agile Methodology, Scrum, Kamban, Trello, Slack

Framework: ASP.NET core, React.js, Express.Js

Database: SQL server (T-SQL), MySql, MariaBD, PostgreSQL, SSIS, ETL, Data warehouse

Business Software: ERP Microsoft Dynamics, WMS Arcante, PLM Porini, ICG POS

Other skills: Office 365 (Excel, Word, Windows), PowerShell, XML, J-son **Soft skills:** Teamwork, creative problem solving, attention to detail, philomath.

PROJECTS

Application personal Budget Android

Application Kottlin Android to handle a personal budget, where the user adds income, expenses and as a result shows a personal balance. It allows adding, editing, deleting transactions and is multilingual.

Environment: Kottlin Android

Code

Environment: C#

Environment: SQL server

Associated with: ISI College Team users: Jhon Diaz

Application full-stack Manager favorite music albums

Environment: Node.js, ReactJs, PostgreSQL Development of a web application for the user to control your list of favorites, searching, adding, and deleting. It was built with a Back-end server using Node is add Express for the REST APIs that manage the PostgreSQL database. The Front-end server is a React is that request the user requirements with RESTful APIs for the Discogs Music. My role in this project was developing the Back-end part.

Associated with: ISI College **Team users:** Anuj Narang and Jhon Diaz Code

MVC application for managing contacts

Application C# for contact management, a graphical interface that allows you to create new contacts, edit existing ones and delete them, these data are stored in text files. In this project worked. In this project, we worked on distributing parts of the menu for the project. In this project, we distributed parts of the menu for the project, and each one coded and tested his part.

Associated with: ISI College **Team users:** Ricardo Castano and Jhon Diaz

Administrador de la base de datos ERP

Developed in Transact-SQL reports and consulting for information analysis and decision-making, creation, reconstruction and reorganization of indexes and update statistics, backups to maintain optimal performance of the company's ERP database.

Associated with: ISI College

EDUCATION

Programming and Web Technologies, Attestation of College Studies	2021 - Present
Institut Supérieur d'Informatique – Montreal, Canada	
Francisation Level 3 FIA109-3, French studies	2022 - Present
Centre Social d'aide aux Immigrants - CSAI – Montreal, Canada	
Production engineer, Bachelor's Degree	2008 - 2013
Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas, Bogotá - Colombia	

Jhon Deiber Diaz Parra (514) 3461672 jhondeiberd@gmail.com CERTIFICATIONS

English - Professional working proficiency French - Elementary proficiency Spanish - Native or bilingual proficiency

Analyzing data with Power BI, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

SQL 2016 Database Development, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

Developing C# - ASP.NET Core MVC, Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA)

Lourtec IT Services and IT Consulting – Remote

Object-oriented programming paradigm

2021 - 2021

Database Administrator (DBA)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Fundación Carlos Slim-Remote

Applications and Database Manager ERP

2017 - 2020

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Implemented agile methodologies for execution and follow-up of projects and developments in Dynamics ERP.
- Supported my team with debugging code in the Dynamics ERP AOT for bug fixes.
- Developed database queries for incident resolution and analysis.
- Monitored the database performance, defined users and enabled the data distribution.
- Database maintenance, indexes, re-indexing, statistics, locks, back-up
- Collaborated with area managers and third-level service companies to identify and resolve problems, coordinated system requirements and created project schedules. Planned and executed annual budget for ERP improvement.
- Planned, implemented and supervised IT technology solutions to ensure satisfactory fulfillment of end-user requirements, implementation and support in a productive environment.
- Coordinated the created of virtual training material for the users' application

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Landscaper 2021 – Present

Boardwalk, Montréal QC, Canada

- Responsible for painting common areas of assigned buildings.
- Responsible for moving the lawns around the buildings.
- Support the maintenance and concierges teams when necessary.

Applications Professional ERP

2008 - 2017

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Escalated problems to the Technical Specialist Level III's or above within the support structure.
- Led the definition and formation of plans for applications aimed to master users' knowledge.
- Performed test runs for approval and implementation of developments in a production environment.
- Enhanced and maintained ERP functionalities and execute upcoming projects.
- Implemented and deployed ERP's standard modules and local functionalities.
- Optimized processes and procedures in the ERP
- Trained the different ERP users in the ERP modules.

Production Planning Analyst

2006 - 2008

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Implemented Material Requirements Planning (MRP) methodology for product production
- Designed and configured technical sheets and spreadsheets for clothing products.
- Calculated the manufacturing route and the cost of the bill of materials for the garments.
- Applied engineering industrialization methods and plans to improve the manufacturing process to optimize operating costs.
- Optimized raw material inventories and allocation based on collection designs.

Production Engineering Analyst

2003 - 2006

Permoda, Bogotá - Colombia

- Designed and enhance workload balancing for production plants.
- Implemented engineering methods and time analysis for the plans' workstations.
- Designed and implement standards time for garments operations.
- Identified and improved bottlenecks for production modules.
- Prepared efficiency reports and control the unproductive time of the plant.